<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: agile | Andy Lind]]></title>
  <link href="http://andylind.github.com/blog/categories/agile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andylind.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-06T23:41:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://andylind.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Lind]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Agile Day Twin Cities 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://andylind.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/agile-day-twin-cities-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T15:35:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andylind.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/agile-day-twin-cities-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday, I attended the <a href="https://sites.google.com/site/twincitiespracticalagility/agile-day-twin-cities-2012">Agile Day Twin Cities</a> conference. The conference was centered around building a discussion about agile software practices and the main theme this year was learning.</p>

<p>I want to share some of the most interesting and thought provoking statements that I heard from the day. Each of these could probably be an entire post on their own, but I think that these anecdotes and insights really give a picture of the discussion at Agile Day and the focus on questioning the status quo.</p>

<p>The first speaker was <a href="https://twitter.com/davidhussman/">David Hussman</a>, who did a great job at getting everyone to question why they are doing things. Here are some of my favorite quotes from his presentations:
<blockquote><p>"Ask why. Why are you changing the process? Could you be doing something more valuable?"<br/>"Minimize output, Maximize impact"<br/>"Transition from thinking about how big something is to thinking if something is too big."<br/>"One sign of a maturing agile team is that they stop talking about the code and they start talking about the tests that they need"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Stemming from David's talk, there was a lot of discussion on why we work in iterations and what life would be like if we moved beyond iterations.
<blockquote><p>"Why does it matter if you don't get done what you committed to in the sprint?"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Another session that I attended was focused on pair-programming practices. During that session the speaker made a really good point about testing:
<blockquote><p>"What is the next test that you should write? The test that tells you the most about the system."</p></blockquote>
This point really hit home for me. I have been trying to transition to using more Test Driven Development (TDD) practices, and I think this could really help guide me in choosing the next test to write.</p>

<p>Throughout the day, I heard a lot of controversial statements about process and tools such as:
<blockquote><p>"JIRA is where stories go to die", and "Project Management is a symptom, not a solution"</p></blockquote>
There was a lot of support at the conference for sticky-note driven workflow, and a lot of backlash against project management tools. I think that was one of the things that I most disagreed with. I have really seen a huge benefit when using a tracking tool to share info about stories among a large team.</p>

<p>The last quote that I found really interesting was from one of the open-space sessions. The speakers described a really great technique that runs counter to a lot of teaching for gathering requirements (e.g. 5 whys):
<blockquote><p>People do not respond well to being asked, "Why?". Instead, ask "If that happened, then what?" or "Pretend you had that, then what would you do?"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Overall, I thought the conference was really good, and I appreciated the focus on continuous improvement throughout the agile process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
