<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Andy Lind]]></title>
  <link href="http://andylind.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andylind.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-26T22:01:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://andylind.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andy Lind]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Most Used Linux Commands]]></title>
    <link href="http://andylind.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/my-most-used-linux-commands/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T13:28:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://andylind.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/my-most-used-linux-commands</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The commands below make up about 90% of what I do on a Linux system. Most of what I do from the command line involves ssh'ing into a server, searching through log files, checking on processes, and editing configuration files. Since I am not doing most of my development work directly on a Linux box, I often find myself forgetting how to do certain tasks, or not knowing how to do something on a specific server. I put together the small guide below with commands that are available on almost any Linux system. By learning these few commands, I have been able to navigate around and get what I need done in almost any Linux environment.</p>

<pre>
#Login to a remote server
ssh [-p port] [username@hostname]
</pre>




<pre>
#List files in a directory with file information
ls -l
</pre>




<pre>
#See every process running on a system
ps aux
</pre>




<pre>
#Print the last 100 lines of a file
tail -100 [filename]
</pre>




<pre>
#Watch a log file as it grows
tail -f [filename]
</pre>




<pre>
#Look for a pattern in a file
grep [pattern] [file]
</pre>




<pre>
#Run an HTTP GET request to a url
curl [url]
</pre>




<pre>
#Change file permissions to read/write for all
chmod a+rw [filename]
</pre>


<p>Here is an example of a common way that I might chain commands together:</p>

<pre>
#Look in the last 1000 lines of a file for lines starting with ERROR
#and print out the matching lines and the 5 lines above and below
tail -1000 logs/logfile.txt | grep ^ERROR -A 5 -B 5
</pre>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
